and we'll call the one of the regular scheduled meeting
on the City Council for Monday, November 4th, 2020, for public input
and let's get the personal appearances.
Have none?
Three, claims list.
Motion to approve the second.
Aye.
Is that double?
Perns, aye.
Perfect.
Aye.
Four.
October 7, 2020, for a regular meeting.
Minutes.
Motion to approve.
Sorry.
Is that all?
Aye.
Perns, aye.
Double.
Aye.
Perfect.
Five.
Budget amendment.
Number 25, dash 11, MCB, eliminating a part-time position, and moving that budget
part-time salary from the MCB part-time salaries to the full-time salaries account
from the MCB fund to the MDRA Main Street fund.
For the increase in coordinator position pay, placed part-time receiving, spending, and portion
of the money is received for a pair, to unit 2203, 22, that are 2224, interceptor.
And receiving and expanding, remaining money for their pairs to a different unit number 2302,
the 2340 interceptor.
That did not receive enough insurance funds to complete your pairs.
Parts receiving and spending money from the Office of Accounting Fairport, to reimburse for
dentorial supplies.
They should have contractually supplied, and to repair downspouts, damaged in the show barn.
The library receipt and the spending money from ARFL conference grant for two library staff members
to attend and receiving the explaining donations for various programs.
There's a law.
I don't know.
It's not a great law.
What you've done in the four minutes.
Out of the budget amendment is taking care of all of that.
where these were unbudgeted funds,
so we're increasing the revenue,
so that we're able to expand out the G.L.s.
No, there's anything that you may have
a particular question on,
and you have the line items that that is what we're doing.
On the, on the, on the,
2023, 2024 in our chapter.
Mm-hmm.
Well, they're not repairing that, we're all.
On which one, the 2020 to you.
I think they're repairing two, two units.
Yes.
Yes, that's fine.
We've talked about it.
So take a look at my money that they've got for my level.
Yes.
Because they're,
There's a total of 5,834 that was received, so we're only taking a portion of that to repair
the unit 2203 and then the remaining to repair the 2023 O2 unit, so we're splitting it up.
So we'll end up with two units.
Yes.
Sorry, I kind of was texting me.
That's a motion to approve.
Second.
So cool.
Hi.
He's deaf.
All right.
Thank you.
Six presentation from Mades.
Shandua.
Mayor Council.
Thank you for the opportunity to be here tonight.
Three things I want to go over real quickly.
I know Tyler's in a hurry to get to watch the game, so I don't want to.
Don't want to waste anymore time.
The first thing I want to talk about is if you remember the housing and demographic study that
Mades is currently working on, the price tag of that came in at just under $50,000.
We have signed the contract with catalysts out of Dallas, Texas.
They've actually already started some of the preliminary work on collecting some of the data.
For that, we have a phone meeting with him tomorrow.
We're going to be reaching out to you.
They want to do a kickoff meeting with you.
As members of the council, to receive any input you have is what you may want from that study.
I know Ben, with Poki.
I know he had some questions.
I think that would be a great opportunity if that kickoff meeting to address some of those issues as well.
So we'll come up with some dates during that conversation tomorrow.
And as I have those dates, I'll relay those to Melissa, and she can get that information out to you.
If you remember this council voted, I believe last month to approve some funds to help with the cost of that study.
Those funds were approved, contingent, upon my next topic I want to talk about, which is the Miami Nustrial Authority Board.
They are meeting tomorrow at four o'clock.
They will be voting on a very important project.
That project is for the sale of property within progress in industrial park.
That project, if approved by MIDA tomorrow, will result in the creation of 24 new jobs for the city of Miami at an annual payroll of $1.1 million.
So these are good jobs there.
I think the lowest starting pay for these new jobs is about $40,000.
So that's important. That's a kind of a target number we have within our organization.
We start talking about creating what we call primary jobs.
That 40 to 45,000 ranges are benchmarked.
So hopefully that meeting goes well.
We can get this property approved.
It's going to allow a company we already have.
to start a new plan and new production facility within the City of Limits of Miami.
They've already been a great partner.
I think we've got a great relationship with them.
Thank you for your support for the Housing Study.
Now it's my job to go get the other part done so we can create those jobs.
Finally, the last thing I want to talk about, I'm the Switch Hats for just a second.
I'm going to put my River Bottom Sportsman hat on and I just want to take the opportunity
to thank the Council, the Mayor, Tyler, Ben, and I'm most of you who came out over the weekend.
To help celebrate our great deer hut.
It's the annual deer hunt we do for disabled paralyzed veterans in our community.
It was a great event.
We had a good turnout.
We had some great individuals, some hunters participating this year.
I want to thank Blessed Parsley.
He came out both days and he didn't just come out and eat.
I want to make that very clear.
Blessed came out and worked.
He served food.
He helped us at anything we needed done.
It meant a lot to us as volunteers, especially to the veterans.
I think on Saturday night, I think it finally registered just how important this event is.
Not only to us as volunteers in our community but to our veterans, bless got to see that first hand.
I think he came close at the time, I couldn't really tell because he was sitting in two people over.
I think his eyes watered up a couple of times during that event.
That Saturday night is very emotional.
It's a very powerful ceremony.
Thank you all for your continued support.
I had to make a couple of phone calls.
He came out with Johnny on the spot.
We can't do it without the support of the city of Miami.
From the bottom of my heart, on behalf of the Rugby Bottom Sportsman, thank you for your support.
Hopefully we can continue this for a long time.
This was our 16th year doing that event in Miami.
Thank you.
Happy to answer any questions you may have.
Try to keep it brief.
I appreciate it.
That was a great event.
I just made it for the launch Friday, but it was really cool to be involved in the fish was really good too.
Good job.
Of course it was.
It was a great event, though.
I really felt honored to be a part of it.
It's one of the most important things to know about how many deer were harvested during the event.
What's funny about that question is that is such a small part of what we do all week
and long, but just to put it in a perspective, because everybody wants to know, they were allowed
12 and 9 were harvested, so not about a week.
Nice.
Thanks.
Thank you.
Pam's real quick.
The housing study?
Yes.
When do you think that would be done?
If we can get the kickoff meeting scheduled within the next two weeks, the completion
day at the entire duration of the report takes about.
weeks. So they can get accurate maybe by the end of the year but certainly by the first part
of January. And we can work just to get a little good work session in order to get
a good work session. Yeah, once we get some options from them when they can be here, we'll
reach out and then we'll see as you guys sign off on the date that works best for you. We'll
get that pencil in and we'll go from there. But the start to finish the whole process takes
about eight weeks. Thank you. So award-least purchase agreements to first ask the bank for 2025,
Pierce Commercial Beat XP Pumper C24-99A, we give really a sign and payment authority
to the city manager or his dead in need. So we later in council, we sent out five solicitations
to get interest rates. And we had two that didn't have a bid. Well, state bank, bank of grand
like the first national office. The interest rates range from 4.98% down to 4.81. We put it on five
year, least purchase solicitation. And first national banks bid came in, a thousand, 4.97, 95 more
in total interest fees and charges than the next closest bid gave us. I touched base with Chris
when I came in. I said, now, how old is the truck that we're replacing? He said, 1980. Well, I think
the other day was in 1988, but I got to figure in that. And this truck, it will, if we go the same
distance, it's time, it'll give us a 261. So that thing needs to be replaced. That's crazy.
You can't say it like that. So anyway, we've 20 minutes. Setting up, please purchase with
our national bank. Listen, Brian. I'll make a motion to approve. Second.
Thank you, Brian. Thank you. Thank you. Thank you. Hi.
Thank you, Chief. Hi, double. Hi. Hey, contract member number 1 for C, 23-53 with clean, uniform
company for uniform services, contingent upon submission of all required contract documents.
Almost two of them, second.
Hi. Hi.
Hi.
Hi. Nine, ordinance C, C, 2024. That's there for, I'm ending chapter 3 of that whole beverage
control by adding section 3-6-101. So council, as I'm sure you know, it's clearly recall after
the up on the boaters and actively up all of their original up on.
like the British control act of the cities to rain by various aspects of the public villages.
The problem was that the legislature kept changing it, and so we had key enormous to manage the changes that they were making.
So ultimately, and I think it's 2023, we passed an ordinance that said we're just accepting the state law as our law.
And whatever changes they make, it becomes our change.
However, it came to find out recently through a case we had in court, but there is a conflict in the state law between
one provision that's in the alcoholic beverage control act, and another one that's entitled 21, which relates to criminal activities.
We would refer to have the one that's in the entitled 21, which, or transporting an open container of alcoholic beverage,
the driver can be charged with the offense, or the passenger who's possession that is in, and being charged with the offense.
Under the alcohol beverage control act, only the driver can be charged.
So this change would adopt the broader law that would allow us to charge either the driver or the passenger who's possession of the alcoholic beverages.
What is the precedent on that, Ben? Is that what other cities are doing across the state?
Everybody's doing across the state is all over the board.
I got you.
And many cities are not keeping up with all the changes that the state's making, which makes it personal, it makes it a whole lot more difficult for law enforcement,
because we've got a figure on that while this industry court, or am I going to follow it in city court, and what's the law in each one?
So our attempt was just to keep us completely in line with what the state law says,
but we find out there's a conflict between two state laws, and so we're just wanting to adopt the driver of the two.
I got you.
I'll make a motion when we approve.
Sorry.
Estep?
Aye.
So, for the time, Parker.
10.
2025.
Holiday schedule.
Most of the two approve.
Aye.
Estep?
So, for the time, Parker.
Aye.
11.
2025.
Top.
Ponds.
E7.
Hi.
12.
American Foundation to reappoint the Jeff Stewart to the airport authority board.
Turn to expire 11.
7.
27.
Motion approved.
2.
Top.
Ponds.
E7.
13.
There's a combination of reappoint Matt Roberts to the airport authority board.
Turn to expire 11.
7.
Motion.
2.
Top.
E7.
4.
14, Mayor's nomination to re-appoint Jeff Howell to the airport authority board turn the expire eleven seven twenty-seven
second
All right, he's step
15, Mayor's nomination to appoint Kevin Duckel to the airport authority board replacing Jim Belcher turn to expire eleven seven twenty-five. Most two proof. Second
He's hit
16, Mayor's nomination to re-appoint Ron Shirley to the city zoning and putting
commission turn the expire ten fifteen and twenty-seven
17, Mayor's nomination to re-appoint Cody Thompson to the city zoning and planning commission turn the expire ten fifteen and twenty-seven
18, new business, maybe what's the reason for this agenda 19, staff reports, 20, Mayor council committee and as well
Yeah, this just do your hunting, I mean the notes are all about the veterans and stuff, but I appreciate that the effort that these guys go through every year
That's honor these veterans and to make it possible for them to
Go out and do something otherwise they wouldn't be capable of doing right on their own
So it's admirable and
Just want to
Another another reason I love my little community
We do so many things like this to
Honor people and I just I enjoy that I love being a part of this artist
And I got a lot of phone calls over the weekend about how our city's
Really stepped up on some of the storm day images and stuff and made it around and helped neighbors clean up
It was awesome
The deer hut has put off a bronze head and looked a chance at earlier
Jack Down Ripple is a special guy
He's probably the kindest, most generous people ever met in my life
He's always willing to do whatever he can for anybody
Have to see the love that he puts into that and change in his career as well
Me, Chan, we're there for three days
And got four days and got hardly any sleep, cooked all these meals.
It was cool just to go be a little part of it.
I didn't do much, but I wouldn't just be a part of it.
And there was one lady, I couldn't look running the Linda.
No, I kind of fell in love with this lady at the assembly,
because she was so happy and so excited.
And her smile was just beaming.
You couldn't get it off her face.
And she was an army veteran.
But she was a beaming year-year.
I didn't find out to a later talking to her,
that she'd never hunted in her life.
And the first day out, she got a buck in the dough.
And they both dressed out about 150 pounds of peas.
And her poor husband was setting her up with this phone.
Trying to figure out how to order a freezer.
She didn't know how to order the dough.
It was really neat just to have a conversation.
And they've been to a lot of my wife's veterans.
And you know, I think we take that for granted a lot of times.
That even though they've been out of the service for 20 years,
they still buy out of demons every day for what they saw,
and what they encountered in the service.
Not only on Shekin's head, because he's got boys during the service.
And so he understands exactly what we're talking about.
But there was another lady.
There was another lady.
She was a little bit late.
I think.
And she stood up at that last night and cried,
because she felt accepted by the people here.
So how many years did she went through,
not feeling accepted until she got here?
And she really felt accepted by the people that were at this event.
But the cold day in the last night,
where he said about cried,
because they'd make them all go outside.
And I didn't know this was going to happen until it was happening.
But of course, she hadn't been there.
But the gun they hunted with, that whole time,
was given to them.
And you should have seen her faces,
because I don't know if anybody's ever really,
I don't know if they've ever got any type of award for what they've done.
And this was kind of a little bit of a payment for what they've been through their whole lives.
It's a great, great event.
And if you can go and you don't have to go and do anything but eat.
There's plenty of food.
You can just shop and eat and just visit with them a little bit.
There's a World War II veteran there.
It was really cool to be in the presence of maybe the best generation we've ever seen in this world.
Those World War II veterans.
But it's just a great event.
It really is.
I'm proud that it's here.
I don't know who came up with the idea or where it originated from.
But whoever it is.
I'm sure it was probably Jack and Chan and they probably.
Well.
But I had beef tongue for the first time.
It was actually pretty good.
Oh, she had a nice one.
She had a nice one.
Yes.
It's good.
But there's plenty of food, I promise.
I think you guys have plenty left over, if you guys could.
Yeah, we don't let anything go.
Yeah.
Okay, we're going to go down there.
Okay.
I guess tomorrow, we'll start decorating, so tomorrow the Christmas decorations start going
up, or make sure you look like it's never looked like before, or at least in a long time.
So I'm going to wait until tornado season ends.
It was supposed to start today, why didn't it?
So they got post-pombed, but anyway, we appreciate your guys.
So we know they're going to be busy for the next couple of weeks, everybody's guys, because
I know everybody's going to be involved.
So we think you guys are there, but I'm excited to see what it's going to look like.
All right, I'm going to say Amanda, she made a carriage.
I'm just having one thing, I'm coming to rain now, so we use our place or ID for the blue hall,
the sweet streets.
We had approximately 3,000 people down there, so that's pretty cool down there.
People down town for that event, so we're trying to show the reason, you know, we've got
members here with this description of the place here, and using this to try to help things out.
So, do we do it, Gerrard?
Well, second.
Five.